John M. Bailey Papers
© 2010 University of Connecticut
John M. Bailey Papers
undated, 1960-1968.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Bailey, John M.
12.3 linear feet.
The collection contains correspondence, photographs, speeches, publications and administrative records created and collected by John M. Bailey, Connecticut lawyer and chairman of the National Democratic Party from 1961-1968.
MSS20070002
Biography
John M. Bailey, born in Hartford, Connecticut, on November 23, 1904. Educated at both Catholic University of America and Harvard Law School, Bailey was a lawyer who and municipal judge in Connecticut (1933-1935, 1939-1941). His involvement in the political arena included membership in the Connecticut Democratic State Central Committee (1932) followed by his service as a delegate to Democratic National Convention from Connecticut (1936, 1940, 1944 [alternate], 1948, 1952, 1956, 1960, 1964 [chair, Arrangements Committee], 1968, 1972). Bailey played an important role in Connecticut's Democratic politics and served as the Connecticut Democratic Party Chairman from 1946 until his death in 1975. Bailey worked for John F. Kennedy's successful presidential campaign in 1960 and then went on to serve as chairman of the National Democratic Party from 1961-1968. A member of the American Bar Association, Knights of Columbus and Elks, John M. Bailey died on April 10, 1975, and is buried in Cedar Hill Cemetery, Hartford, Connecticut.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence, photographs, speeches, publications and administrative records created and collected by John M. Bailey.
Arrangement
An inventory of the materials has been created to provide access to the materials. The collection is arranged as received.
Related Material
For detailed information about this collection please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Bailey, John M.
Organizations:
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Publications.; Photographs.; Administrative Records.; Speeches.; Contracts.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by the family in 2007 and 2009.
Detailed Description
- Inventory, undated, 1960-1968
  - Virginia, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Virgin Islands, 1967
  - Washington, 1967
  - West Virginia, 1967
  - Wisconsin, 1967
  - Wyoming, 1967
  - Oregon, 1967
  - Puerto Rico, 1967
  - Rhode Island, 1967
  - South Carolina, 1967
  - South Dakota, 1967
  - Tennessee, 1967
  - Texas, 1967
  - Utah, 1967
  - North Dakota, 1967
  - Ohio, 1967
  - Oklahoma, 1967
  - Pennsylvania, 1967
  - New York, 1967
  - North Carolina, 1967
  - New Jersey, 1967
  - New Mexico, 1967
  - Iowa, 1967
  - Kentucky, 1967
  - Massachusetts, 1967
  - Maryland, 1967
  - Kansas, 1967
  - Louisiana, 1967
  - Maine, 1967
  - Michigan, 1967
  - Minnesota, 1967
  - Mississippi, 1967
  - Missouri, 1967
  - Montana, 1967
  - Nebraska, 1967
  - Nevada, 1967
  - New Hampshire, undated
  - Chairman Bailey's Speeches, undated (Box 2)
  - New York-Las Vegas, undated
  - Travel Schedules, undated
  - TV & Radio, undated
  - Albany, April 29
  - Ogdensburg, April 29
  - Buffalo, April 24
  - Jamestown, April 24
  - Rochester, April 25
  - Syracuse, Utica, undated
  - Trinity College, undated
  - DNC Meeting, January 11, 1960
  - DNC Meeting, 1961
  - Committees, undated
  - Site, undated
  - Resolutions, undated
  - Atlanta, Georgia Conference, undated
  - Inauguration, 1961
  - Atlanta, Georgia Regional Conference, 1961 February 23-24
  - Dallas Conference, undated [February 9-10]
  - Springfield, Illinois, undated [March 8-9]
  - Providence, Rhode Island, 1968 March 15-16
  - Pennsylvania Regional Conference, undated [March 22-23]
  - Speeches, undated
  - Correspondence, undated
  - Resolutions from DNC Meetings, undated
  - Programs for DNC, undated
  - Leventhal, undated (Box 3)
  - Contests, undated
  - Unanswered mail, 1968
  - News Releases, 1968
  - Telegrams, 1968
  - DNC Meeting, 1966 April 20
  - Special Committee, undated
  - O'Brien Reports, undated
  - Correspondence to White House, undated
  - President Kennedy, undated
  - President Johnson, undated
  - Clubs, undated
  - Campaign, undated
  - Western State Conference, 1963
  - Memberships, undated
  - Biographical data, undated
  - CT Democratic Committee, undated
  - Midwest Conference, 1963
  - Mississippi, undated
  - Chairman Bailey-Personal, undated (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, undated
  - Convention Material, 1963
  - Chairman Bailey-Press Conferences, undated
  - Commerce Department, undated
  - Condolences, undated
  - Senators and Congressmen, undated
  - Cape Committee, 1967
  - Crank Mail, 1967
  - Federal Campaign Fund Advisory Board, undated
  - Foreign Countries Correspondence, 1967
  - Vice President Humphrey, undated
  - Governor's Aides Conference, undated
  - Correspondence, undated
  - DNC Interoffice Memos, 1967
  - Invitations Completed, 1967
  - Invitations Completed, 1967
  - Invitations Completed, 1967
  - Affirmation of Support of Candidates, 1960
  - Democratic Legislateive Leader's Conference, undated
  - Midwest Conference, 1967
  - Minorities Division-DNC, undated
  - DNC Nationalities Division, undated
  - Press Releases, 1967
  - National Committee Meeting, 1967 October 9
  - National Committeemen, undated
  - DNC-Operation Support, undated (Box 5)
  - DNC-Open House, undated
  - DNC-Personnel, undated
  - DNC-Equal Rights Committee, undated
  - Republican National Committee, undated
  - President-White House, undated
  - DNC-Registration, Billie Farnum, 1967
  - DNC-Research and Publications, undated
  - Romney, undated
  - DNC-Registration Division, undated
  - Speaker's Bureau, undated
  - DNC-National Committee Meeting, 1967 March 10-11
  - State Chairman and Vice Chairman Meeting, 1967 March 30-31
  - Salute to the President Dinner, 1967 October 7
  - Site Committee, 1967
  - Telegram, undated
  - Unanswered Mail, undated
  - Thank You's, undated
  - Volunteer Work, 1967
  - Western State Conferences, undated
  - Women's Division, undated
  - National Committee Women, undated
  - DNC-Young Americans Division, undated
  - Press Clippings, undated
  - DNC-News Releases, undated
  - Alabama, undated (Box 6)
  - Alaska, undated
  - Arizona, undated
  - Arkansas, undated
  - California, undated
  - Colorado, undated
  - Connecticut, undated
  - Delaware, undated
  - District of Columbia, undated
  - Florida, undated
  - Georgia, undated
  - Hawaii, undated
  - Idaho, undated
  - Illinois, undated
  - Indiana, undated
  - Iowa, undated
  - Kansas, undated
  - Kentucky, undated
  - Louisiana, undated
  - Maine, undated
  - Maryland, undated
  - Massachusetts, undated
  - Minnesota, undated
  - Mississippi, undated
  - Missouri, undated
  - Montana, undated
  - Nebraska, undated
  - Nevada, undated
  - New Hampshire, undated
  - New Jersey, undated
  - New Mexico, undated
  - New York, undated
  - North Carolina, undated
  - North Dakota, undated
  - Ohio, undated
  - Oklahoma, undated (Box 7)
  - Oregon, undated
  - Pennsylvania, undated
  - Puerto Rico, undated
  - Rhode Island, undated
  - South Carolina, undated
  - South Dakota, undated
  - Tennessee, undated
  - Texas, undated
  - Utah, undated
  - Vermont, undated
  - Virginia, undated
  - Washington, undated
  - West Virginia, undated
  - Wisconsin, undated
  - Wyoming, undated
  - Foreign Mail, undated
  - Alaska, 1967
  - Arizona, undated
  - Arkansas, undated
  - California, undated
  - Canal Zone, undated
  - Colorado, undated
  - Connecticut, undated
  - Delaware, undated
  - District of Columbia, undated
  - Florida, undated
  - Georgia, undated
  - Guam, undated
  - Hawaii, undated
  - Idaho, undated
  - Illinois, undated
  - Indiana, undated
  - Press Clippings, 1968
  - A Correspondence, undated (Box 8)
  - B Correspondence, undated
  - C Correspondence, undated
  - D Correspondence, undated
  - E Correspondence, undated
  - F Correspondence, undated
  - G Correspondence, undated
  - H Correspondence, undated
  - I Correspondence, undated
  - J Correspondence, undated
  - K Correspondence, undated
  - L Correspondence, undated
  - M Correspondence, undated
  - N Correspondence, undated
  - O Correspondence, undated
  - P Correspondence, undated
  - Q Correspondence, undated
  - R Correspondence, undated
  - S Correspondence, undated
  - T Correspondence, undated
  - U Correspondence, undated
  - V Correspondence, undated
  - W Correspondence, undated
  - Y Correspondence, undated
  - Z Correspondence, undated
  - Alabama, undated
  - Alaska, undated
  - Arizona, undated
  - Arkansas, undated
  - California, undated
  - Colorado, undated
  - Connecticut, undated
  - Delaware, undated
  - District of Columbia, undated
  - Florida, undated
  - Georgia, undated
  - Hawaii, undated
  - Idaho, undated
  - Illinois, undated
  - Indiana, undated
  - Iowa, undated
  - Kansas, undated
  - Kentucky, undated
  - Louisiana, undated
  - Maine, undated
  - Maryland, undated
  - Massachusetts, undated
  - Minnesota, undated
  - Mississippi, undated
  - Missouri, undated
  - Montana, undated
  - Nebraska, undated
  - Nevada, undated
  - New York, undated (Box 9)
  - North Carolina, undated
  - North Dakota, undated
  - Ohio, undated
  - Oregon, undated
  - Pennsylvania, undated
  - Puerto Rico, undated
  - Rhode Island, undated
  - South Carolina, undated
  - South Dakota, undated
  - Tennessee, undated
  - Texas, undated
  - Utah, undated
  - Vermont, undated
  - Virginia, undated
  - Washington, undated
  - West Virginia, undated
  - Wisconsin, undated
  - Wyoming, undated
  - Guam, undated
  - Announcements, undated
  - Anti-Johnson Mail Received, 1968
  - Bailey-Speeches, 1968
  - Correspondence, undated
  - Invitations, undated
  - National Committeemen and National Committeewomen, 1968
  - Regional Meetings, 1968
  - Newsclippings, undated
  - Scrapbook, undated (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, undated
  - Scrapbook, undated
  - Event and family photos, undated
  - Presidential Race Cartoon, undated